# 红的绿的颜色多漂亮
Look how beautiful these red and green are
# 香味出来了
The aroma has came out
# 咱今天炒一合菜大爷
Let's cook a Chao He Cai (stir-fry combo) today, Da Ye
# 马上过完年要咬春了
It's almost the end of the spring festival and Yao Chun is about to come.
# 有好菜还得有好饼
A delicious dish has to go with some great wraps
# 今天就着你这合菜
Together with your He Cai today,
# 大爷给做一个春饼
Da Ye makes a Chun Bing (wraps?)
# 得勒得我先把面烫上
Alright, let me start making the dough
# 二伯那眼睛斜着看着呢
Er Bai is peeking you on the side
# 刚子我这边揉着面
Gang Zi while i'm needing the dough,
# 你们这边该准备什么料
you guys continue with your preparation
# 准备什么料得嘞大爷
What do we need to prepare? No problems Da Ye.
# 片肉丝吧 我给你来一特写啊
Slice pork tenderloins, let me do a close up shot on you
# 猪通脊 通脊肉长在哪儿啊
Pork tenderloins, which part of the pork is it?
# 脊背啊 小脊背
At the back, within the loin.
# 这片的还不错啊 童子功
You are doing well, you must be working hard on this for ages.
# 其实炒合菜还是肥瘦的好
Actually it's best to have some fatty parts together with lean parts when cooking Chao He Cai.
# 肥瘦好吃 大爷说话了
Best to have fat and lean, said Da Ye.
# 肥瘦的它香啊
It's aroma is irresistible!
# 切肉丝左手要像螃蟹一样
Your left hand should be like a crab when you julienne meat
# 倒着走 就是退
Crawling backwards
# 这手法 这就是烙饼面软软乎乎的
Check out the technique, these wraps come out soft and fluffy
# 烫完以后没有这么大的筋络（劲儿）了
It's not as sticky as before (less gluten)
# 你这个瘦的还真得上浆
Yours are too lean, gotta cover it with some starchy water
# 上浆 要不然不嫩啊
For sure, otherwise it won't be tender.
# 少来点肉丝就行了
A little bit of julienned pork is enough
# 搁点盐
A bit of salt
# 刚才的葱姜水 好
Ginger and scallion infused water, that will do.
# 胡椒粉 蛋清半个蛋清
a bit of ground peppercorn and half of an egg white
# 你师父上浆刨肉厉害 真嫩啊
Your master is really good at covering meat with starchy water, so tender!
# 玉米淀粉 够吗师父 够了
Corn starch, is that enough master?
# 封上油 多封点
Seal it with oil, be generous with the oil
# 二伯封油起什么作用
Er Bai why do we seal it with oil?
# 封完油一个是润
It moisturizes the dish
# 再一个它滑油时候不互相粘连
And it prevents the meat from sticking to each other
# 你看刚才 现在多润
Look how much more moisture it is now
# 抹上油二合一了
It combines the two into one
# 烧点水 二合一了
Get some water boiled, two into one.
# 胡萝卜 韭菜 粉丝
Carrots, chives and vermicelli
# 豆芽讲究 掐菜了（掐头去尾）
You can tell these bean sprouts were prepared in utmost care, picked out heads and tails
# 红嘴绿鹦哥必须得留根
Hong Zui Lv Ying Ge (baby spinach), must keep the roots on
# 老北京讲究这个 小菠菜
It's quite a tradition in Beijing, baby spinach.
# 按过去这说还缺东西
We are missing something if we were back in the good old days.
# 你看馓子或者咯吱盒
Sa Zi (deep fried noodles) or Ge Zi He
# 馓子是最好现在 配着卷着吃 香
Sa Zi is best to be rolled in wraps
# 还缺一样小肚
And one more thing, Xiao Du
# 熏的小肚然后配上酱肉那绝对好
Smoked Xiao Du with stock braised meat that's absolutely amazing
# 焯水给它去掉一下豆芽的豆腥味
Quickly pass it through boiling water to get rig of it's unpleasant smell
# 胡萝卜丝 饼可以上铛了
shred carrot, you can now put the on the pan
# 有点那意思是吧
You can feel that right?
# 断生就行 对待会儿炒呢
Just to soften it, we still need to stir-fry it later
# 这饼好
This wrap is great!
# 擀的时候搁案板搁点油 它不粘
Use some oil to prevent it from sticking on the board when rolling it.
# 卷饼皮不不见得薄就好
It's not always the best to roll it thin.
# 它有面香和菜的冲撞香气
It has the flavor of both flour and veggies.
# 因为太薄了全是菜味
You will only taste the veggies if you roll it too thin
# 您就吃菜就得了
You can just have the veggies by themselves
# 一定要有面香在里头
You have to have the aroma of flour in it.
# 抹点油它烙的有黄嘎巴
A bit of oil on it gives it the golden crust
# 小饼好了 太有食欲了
Our little wraps are done, it looks so alluring
# 这是要搁蒸锅里嘘着
Let it rest in a steamer
# 拿着吃烫嘴 好吃
It still tastes good even if it's too hot to the mouth
# 现烙的面香味
The aroma of freshly made wraps.
# 大爷烙饼继续烙你这边准备着
Go on with your wraps and we'll just prepare the rest on the other side
# 两勺油 下肉丝
Two spoons of oil, in goes julienned pork
# 你看这温度正好
It's on the perfect temperature
# 别着急 下锅千万不用着急
No rush
# 走 趟一下 专业术语
Here we go, Tang it real quick. This is a kitchen jargon
# 这个时候加快速度了啊
Speed it up a little now
# 把疙瘩打匀
Loosen those lumps
# 师父浆的肉丝也好
Master did a great job on moisturizing the meat
# 三叔指导的也好
San Shi gave some great instructions
# 断生就行
Just to soften it
# 油锅一定烧冒烟以后一放凉油
As soon as the oil smokes
# 它的温度滑肉丝正好 三成
It's in the perfect temperature for julienned pork, about 30%
# 炝点花椒粒
Fry some Sichuan peppercorns
# 来点香油 二合油又来了啊
In goes some sesame oil, yet another time we use mixed oil
# 必须得香油 香油好吃
Sesame oil is a must, it tastes so good.
# 慢慢煸炒出香味
Slowly release the aroma
# 这花椒搁晚了之后一激
If peppercorns were added too late
# 要不就糊了
It's either easily burnt
# 要么就里面没味没发挥出来
Or the flavor isn't released out
# 没错 慢慢煸炒要这个香味
You are right, you need to work it slowly to bring out the aroma
# 先放姜后放葱
Gingers go in the wok first then scallions
# 先把姜味冲击出来
In order to bring out the aroma of gingers
# 因为葱花易黄
Also because scallions are easily browned
# 先放肉丝你怎么不先放菜啊
Why don't you add those veggies first
# 入一下味 你这手法有点反了
to infuse it with some flavor. you did it the other way around
# 一通百通 一定记住先放菜
You can apply the same principle to everything, remember always add veggies first
# 一块全下去
just dump everything in all in once
# 菠菜 粉丝
baby spinach, vermicelli
# 这个韭菜最后吧
these chives come last
# 先烹酒后搁盐啊
Be sure to add wine before salt
# 要不然你肉丝扒锅放那么早
Or else these julienned tenderloins will stick to the wok
# 是不是大爷
Am I right Da Ye?
# 再来点酱油
A bit more soy sauce
# 红的绿的颜色多漂亮
Red and green looks good
# 来点胡椒粉
Add a little bit of ground peppercorn
# 断生就行
Just to soften it
# 尝尝够咸不 再来点酱油
Taste if it's salty enough, do we need to add more soy sauce
# 好 漂亮 这回够咸了
Alright, now it's salty enough
# 韭菜最后放进去 香味出来喽
Lastly we add the chives, the aroma comes out immediately
# 这韭菜够粗的啊
These chives are pretty thick
# 来点香油 光要（韭菜）根利落啊
Can I have some sesame oil please?
# 好 香油
No problems, sesame oil coming!
# 饼也好了 大盘子
And wraps are cooked, big plate!
# 最后搁韭菜就是炝出韭菜的清香味
Adding chives at last was to bring out the freshness of chives
# 这颜色正合适 颜色漂亮
The color is just perfect
# 出锅 为什么叫合菜啊
Done, why it is called He Cai
# 鸡蛋呢 鸡蛋待会盖帽儿盖上
Where are the eggs? later we will cover the dish with fried eggs
# 菜出来了 摊鸡蛋吧
The veggies are out, lets fry some eggs
# 搁点盐
A bit of salt
# 你看见没有 鸡蛋里边放葱花绝配
Look at that, scallions and eggs are the perfect combo.
# 过去我们往里头搁点大油
In the past we would add pork fat in it.
# 鸡蛋吃嘴里它润
moisturizes the eggs when you eat it.
# 分两步炒 师父您给我少倒点
Let's cook it in two run, Master can you please pour in less of it.
# 不全倒上
Not the whole bowl
# 油少 再来点油油太少啦
Not enough oil, give me more oil!
# 这是最笨的招
This is the simplest technique,
# 这是技巧 炒一半留一半
fry it in two go.
# 要不不容易熟
Otherwise it's hard to cook
# 油一开始得宽
You need lots of oil to start.
# 一下给它蓬起来
Puff up these eggs
# 一下就蓬起来了
# 香味出来了
The aroma has came out
# 这会就开始把油给篦出去了
Now we strain out the oil
# 这没问题 金黄色
No problems, golden brown
# 慢点走你
Take it slowly
# 你看这鸡蛋焦黄
Look at the gold brown on the eggs
# 这时候把油空出来
Now we strain out the oil
看着油多其实没那么多油
# 全出去了 喧呼劲儿没了
It's all gone, the greasiness has vanished
# 盖上吧 得嘞出锅喽
Cover it up, fresh off the wok
# 这么一盖 漂亮
Just cover it up, what a beauty
# 卷上了啊 卷福卷财卷起来
Wrap it up! With luck with wealth wrap them all up.
# 卷个烙饼不漏财
Wrap a roll, money won't go
# 你得先得给大爷你别自己吃
Let Da Ye eat first before yourself
# 先给大爷
Give it to Da Ye first
# 我终于给您要过来了
I finally got it for you
# 卷起来卷起来 卷起烙饼就发财
Let us roll let us roll, once you roll money come to you
# 马上就要立春了
We are near the beginning of spring
# 今天合菜炒的好
The He Cai we cooked is good
# 大爷的饼烙的更好
Da Ye's wrap is even better
# 老三的来了
Here comes Lao San's
# 卷财卷福谢谢师父
Wrap luck wrap wealth, thank you master for your help.
# 小喇叭吹起来鼠年发大财
Let's blow that horn and wish everybody a wealthy new year of rat
# 我们小哥俩祝三位老家儿
Two of us juniors wish you three seniors,
# 鼠年发大财鼠年健康
Become wealthy and stay healthy in the year of rat
# 鼠年大吉
All the best in the year of rat
# 先二伯咬一口 真好吃
Let Er Bo have a bite of it, umm it's so good
# 师父来一口
Have a bite Master
# 后面是固定片尾，时间轴需要调整
# TODO: 将片尾时间轴开始时间调整为 7:31.2，以及格式修改为 srt
0:09:49.500,0:09:50.480
# 我是大爷
I am Da Ye
0:09:50.480,0:09:51.260
# 我是二伯
I am Er Bai
0:09:51.260,0:09:52.280
# 我是三叔
I am San Shu
0:09:52.280,0:09:54.520
# 我们是老饭骨
We are Lao Fan Gu
0:09:54.520,0:09:57.820
# 欢迎大家订阅我们老饭骨 YouTube 频道
Please subscribe to our YouTube Channel
0:09:57.820,0:10:00.535
# 我们老饭骨组合就是教大家做菜
We are here to teach you how to cook
0:10:00.540,0:10:02.700
# 传授一些精湛的小厨艺
And to share with you some little tips
0:10:02.700,0:10:03.760
# 希望大家喜欢
Hope you like them
0:10:03.760,0:10:06.520
# 希望全球的美食爱好者喜欢我们
We that hope everyone around the world likes our videos
0:10:06.980,0:10:08.440
# 订阅我们的频道
Subscribe to our channel
0:10:08.440,0:10:10.040
# 点亮我们的小铃铛
Click the notification bell
0:10:10.040,0:10:12.380
# 同时在这里我们祝全球华人
Here, we wish everyone
0:10:12.380,0:10:15.380
# 万事如意 恭喜发财
A lot of happiness and fortune in the coming new year!